urbanindustry.co.uk 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy – Urban Industry

We respect privacy and your rights to control your personal data. Our principle guidelines are simple. We will be clear about the data we collect and why. Your data is highly valued and securely protected by us. We do not and will not sell your data to third parties.The prime purpose of collecting your data is to improve your shopping experience, our aim is for you to shop for your favourite brands and products as effortlessly as possible.

This Privacy Statement (the 'Statement') explains the personal information we collect from you, either directly or indirectly, and how we will use it. Personal information is any information that can be used to identify you or that we can link to you. The Statement also elaborates on the choices you can make about the data we collect, and how you can control these decisions. It applies to all products offered by Urban Industries Ltd ('Urban Industries Ltd Product(s)'). It also applies to any Urban Industries Ltd-controlled websites, as well as other offline interactions, such as visiting a Urban Industries Ltd store or attending a Urban Industries Ltd event (collectively referred to as, 'Services'). Please read this Statement carefully to understand how Urban Industries Ltd may collect, use and share your personal information. The terms 'we', 'us', or 'Urban Industries Ltd' are each intended as reference to Urban Industries Ltd.

**The Types of Personal Information We Collect**

**Information you provide to us**

We collect information you voluntarily provide to us, such as your name, phone number and email address; for instance, when you want to learn more about Urban Industries Ltd Products and Services or when you contact our Customer Services team for assistance with the products you buy from Urban Industries Ltd.

**Information we collect automatically**

We automatically collect information about you, such as Functional Data and Additional Usage Data this regards your use of your Urban Industries Ltd Product or information collected by cookies and similar technologies when you use, access or interact with us via our websites. We may, for example, collect information about the type of device you use to access our websites, the operating system and version, your IP address, your general geographic location, as indicated by your IP address, your browser type, the web pages you view on our websites, whether you interact with content available on our websites and how.

**Information obtained from other sources**

We may receive information about you from other sources, including third parties, such as co-branded services or engage in joint-marketing activities. We may also receive information about you from social media platforms, for instance, when you interact with us on those platforms. We protect data obtained from third parties according to the practices described in this Statement and we also apply any additional restrictions imposed by the source of data.

**Information of children**

Urban Industries Ltd does not target and is not intended to attract children under the age of sixteen. Although visitors of all ages may navigate through our website we do not knowingly collect or request personal information from those under the age of sixteen. If, following a notification from a parent, guardian or discovery by other means, a child under sixteen has been improperly registered on our site by using false information, we will cancel the child's account and delete the child's personal information from our records.

**Customer Interactions with Urban Industries Ltd**

To make the information in this Statement easy to understand, we have highlighted different occasions when Urban Industries Ltd could potentially collect personal information from customers. The customer interactions with Urban Industries Ltd are broken down into the following segments:

**Learning about Urban Industries Ltd**

As you gather more information about Urban Industries Ltd, you may virtually or physically visit a site that we own. Examples include browsing our website, calling our sales representatives, physically visiting a Urban Industries Ltd-owned store or attending Urban Industries Ltd-sponsored events. To learn more about Urban Industries Ltd Products, you may voluntarily provide personal information, such as your name and email address during these interactions. We may also collect information about you online via Cookies and similar technologies when you visit our websites.

**We collect:** name, email address, IP address, and information provided by cookies or similar technology.

**Why:** We use this information to share news about events and products offered by Urban Industries Ltd. Additionally, the IP address helps us to understand geographic information about our website visitors better, so that we can improve our website for everyone. It is our legitimate interest to process your personal data for these purposes.

**Buying Urban Industries Ltd Products**

Once you have decided to buy an Urban Industries Ltd Product, we offer a way for customers to buy directly from us at www.urbanindustry.co.uk or at a Urban Industries Ltd retail store. When you buy from us, you may be asked to provide information so that we can complete your purchase.

**We collect:** your name, phone number (optional), email address, delivery/shipping address, and payment information.

**Why:** We use this information to complete your transaction, carry out any follow up with you about your purchase, help with any delivery issues, handle returns, and other issues related to the purchase of Urban Industries Ltd Products. Processing your personal data for this purpose is necessary for the performance of the agreement we have with you. **Please note, we do not store any payment or credit card information. We only use payment information in connection with the purchase of Urban Industries Ltd Products.**

**Getting Help from Urban Industries Ltd**

From time to time, you may decide to contact our Customer Service Team for assistance with your Urban Industries Ltd Products. To be able to offer you the best service possible, we may collect certain data from you or your Urban Industries Ltd Products.

**We collect:** This may include contact information, such as your name, email address, phone number, social media identifiers (if you contact us using a social media channel), and the content of your chats and other communications with the Urban Industries Ltd Service Team (including voice recording if you call Customer Service Team in business closed hours).

**Why:** We collect this information to give you the best and most efficient customer support possible. For instance, for customer inquiries and product questions, we use contact information to respond to the customer in their preferred channel (phone, email, social). For product returns and/or exchanges, we use contact information to ensure successful product receipt and/or delivery. Using these types of data is necessary to fulfil the agreement we have with you.

**How We Use Personal Information**

Urban Industries Ltd uses the data we collect to provide you with the Products and Services we offer. We also use the data to communicate with you, for example, informing you about your account, new products or services available, security and other types of updates.

Urban Industries Ltd uses the data for the following purposes:

**Providing our Product Experience**

We use data to provide, operate, support and improve the Urban Industries Ltd Products and Services we offer. This processing is necessary for the performance of the agreement we have with you.

**Customer Support**

We use data to respond to customer enquiries, diagnose Product problems, organise the return of customers' Urban Industries Ltd Products and provide other customer care and support services. This processing is necessary for the performance of the agreement we have with you, as well as to serve our legitimate interest.

**Security, Safety and Dispute Resolution**

We use data to protect the security and safety of our Urban Industries Ltd Products and our customers, to detect and prevent fraud, to resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest.

**Business Operations**

We use data to develop aggregate analysis and business intelligence that enable us to operate, protect, make informed decisions, and report on the performance of our business. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest.

**Communication, Marketing and Advertising -**

We use the data you supply to us to deliver and personalise our communications with you. For example, we may contact you by email or other means of electronic communication to inform you about new Urban Industries Ltd Products or Services, update you on a support issue, invite you to take part in a survey or ask for feedback. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest. We also use cookies and similar technologies to provide the most relevant Urban Industries Ltd advertising to you. You can opt out at any time.

To give you a better understanding of the personal information we collect and use in different occasions you may interact with Urban Industries Ltd, please see the sections below. 

**How We May Share Personal Information**

**Urban Industries Ltd does not and will not sell personal information about our customers.**

We only disclose your data as described in this Statement. We may share information with the following types of third parties.

**Third Party Vendors**

Urban Industries Ltd uses a variety of third-party vendors to carry out services like website management and hosting, online Product purchases and shipping, credit card processing and email communications. We only share your personal data as necessary. To complete a transaction, provide a Product or Service you have requested or authorised and only with vendors or agents working on our behalf for the purposes described in this Statement. In this case, your personal information will be shared with these agents or contractors but only for the purpose of performing services on behalf of Urban Industries Ltd and in accordance with this Statement. It is our legitimate interest to process your personal data for these purposes. For questions about third-party vendors, please send an email to privacy@urbanindustry.co.uk

**Urban Industries Ltd-controlled affiliates and subsidiaries**

We share information with Urban Industries Ltd-controlled affiliates and subsidiaries for business purposes, such as, internal administration, promoting Urban Industries Ltd Products and providing customers with our Urban Industries Ltd Products and Services. It is our legitimate interest to process your personal data for these purposes.

**Compelled Disclosure**

When legally required, strictly necessary for the performance of the services or to protect our rights, or the rights of our affiliates or users, we disclose your personal information to law enforcement authorities, investigative organisations, our affiliates or in legal proceedings.

**Sale or Merger**

We may share your personal information in the event of a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets. Of course, we shall notify you via email and/or a prominent notice on our website and inform you of your rights.

**Sharing and Disclosure of Aggregate Data**

We share data in aggregate form and/or in a form which does not enable the recipient of such data to identify you, with third parties, for example, for industry analysis.

Please note, our Products include links to Products or applications of third parties whose privacy practices may differ from Urban Industries Ltd. If you provide personal data to any of those third parties or their products, your data is governed by their privacy statements, and we encourage you to read these privacy statements carefully.

When sharing data with third parties, your personal information may be transferred to countries where data protection laws may provide a lower standard of protection for your personal information than your country. We take great care in protecting your personal information and have put in place adequate mechanisms to protect it when it is transferred internationally. We will transfer your personal information in compliance with applicable data protection laws and will implement suitable safeguards to ensure that your personal information is adequately secured by any third party that will access your information (for instance, by using the Standard Contractual Clauses as approved by the European Commission). If you have questions or wish to obtain more information about the international transfer of your personal information or the implemented safeguards, please send us an email to privacy@urbanindustry.co.uk.

**The Legal Bases for Using Personal Information**

There are different legal bases that we rely on to use your personal information, namely:

**Performance of a contract**

The use of your personal information may be necessary to perform the agreement you have with us. For example, to complete your purchase of your Urban Industries Ltd Product, to register and maintain your account, to help with delivery issues, to handle returns or to respond to your requests.

**Legitimate interests**

We may use your personal information for our legitimate interests. For example, we rely on our legitimate interest to analyse and improve our Urban Industries Ltd Products and Services and the content on our websites to send you notifications or information about Urban Industries Ltd Products and Services or to use your personal information for administrative, fraud detection or legal purposes.

Where we process your personal information based on our legitimate interest and no opt-out mechanism is available. You may exercise your right to object by sending an email to privacy@urbanindustry.co.uk.

**Security, Storage and Retention of Personal Information We Collect**

**Security**

Urban Industries Ltd is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. However, while we take reasonable precautions to guard the personal information we collect, no security system is impenetrable.

While no Service is completely secure, Urban Industries Ltd takes precautionary measures to help prevent information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. For example, we store the personal data you provide on computer systems that have limited access and that are in controlled facilities. We also ensure that our third-party data centre vendors provide adequate security measures. Additionally, your data is protected with encryption, such as Transport Layer Security (TLS), during transition over the Internet. Please note, your password is stored using one-way hash, which means that it cannot be recovered (or disclosed) by anyone, including Urban Industries Ltd, it can only be reset.

You can only access your Urban Industries Ltd account information and our service through the use of an individual user login and password. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. Please notify us immediately if you believe your password has been misused. You should always log out and close your browser when you finish your session. **Please note, we will never ask you to disclose your password in an unsolicited phone call or email.**

If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at privacy@urbanindustry.co.uk.

**Storage**

Personal data collected by Urban Industries Ltd may be stored and processed in your region, in the United States (for example, in our major data centres), or in any other country where Urban Industries Ltd or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers are located or maintain facilities. Urban Industries Ltd has put in place adequate mechanisms to protect personal information when it is transferred internationally, for example by using the Standard Contractual Clauses as approved by the European Commission.

**Retention**

Urban Industries Ltd will retain your personal information for as long as we deem it necessary to enable you to use the website and your Urban Industries Ltd Product, to provide services to you, to comply with applicable laws (including those regarding document retention), resolve disputes with any parties and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business. All personal information we retain will be subject to this Privacy Statement and our internal retention guidelines. If you have a question about a specific retention period for certain types of personal information we process about you, please send an email to privacy@urbanindustry.co.uk.

**Your Rights and Choices**

**Your Rights**

We want you to be in control of how your personal information is used by us. Subject to local law, you can do this in the following ways:

  * you can ask us for a copy of the personal information we hold about you;
  * you can inform us of any changes to your personal information, or if you want us to correct any of the personal information we hold about you;
  * in certain situations, you can ask us to erase, block or restrict the personal information we hold about you, or object to particular ways in which we are using your personal information; and
  * in certain situations, you can also ask us to send the personal information you have given us to a third party.

Where we are using your personal information on the basis of your consent, you are entitled to withdraw that consent at any time. Moreover, where we process your personal information based on legitimate interest or the public interest, you have the **right to object at any time** to that use of your personal information.

We rely on you to ensure that your personal information is complete, accurate and up to date. Please do inform us promptly of any changes to or inaccuracies in your personal information by contacting privacy@urbanindustry.co.uk.

We will respond to your request as soon as possible but certainly within 30 days. For more information about how you can control the collection and use of Communication, Marketing and Advertising Preferences, please view ‘Your Choices’ sections below.

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern you may have about our use of your personal information. If, however, you believe that we have not been able to assist with your complaint or concern, you may have the right to file a complaint with the data protection authority in your country (if one exists in your country) or supervisory authority.

**Your Choices**

**Urban Industries Ltd Account**

If you wish to access, edit or remove profile information, change your password, close your account or request deletion of your personal data, you can do so by sending an email to privacy@urbanindustry.co.uk. If you cannot access certain personal information collected by Urban Industries Ltd, via the Urban Industries Ltd account you can always contact us by sending an email to privacy@urbanindustry.co.uk. We will respond to any request to access or delete your personal data as soon as possible, certainly within 30 days.

**Your Communication, Marketing and Advertising Preferences**

You can opt out of receiving direct marketing communications from Urban Industries Ltd by following the instructions included in every email sent to you via the “Unsubscribe” text link. We respect your choice, and we will stop sending you promotional emails once you unsubscribe.

Please note, regardless of your communication settings, we will continue to communicate with you regarding changes to terms and conditions, policy updates, Urban Industries Ltd Product software updates, routine customer service messages such as information about current or past purchase, delivery of products, service interruptions, data breaches or other significant information about a Product you own, such as safety issues.

If you have opted out of receiving emails from us, we will not use your email for interest-based advertising activities. For more information about our use of interest-based advertising, please visit Our Use of Cookies and Other Similar Technologies below.

### **Our Use of Cookies and Other Similar Technologies**

We use cookies and similar technologies like pixels, tags, web beacons, and other identifiers to help us personalise our website for you, remember your preferences, understand how users are using our website, and help customise our marketing offerings.

##### **Cookies**

A cookie is a small data file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer when you visit a website. When you visit the website again, the cookie allows that site to recognise your browser. The length of time a cookie will stay on your computer or mobile device depends on whether it is a "persistent" or "session" cookie. Urban Industries Ltd uses both types of cookies. Session cookies will only stay on your device until you stop browsing. Persistent cookies stay on your computer or mobile device until they expire or are deleted. We use the following types of cookies on our website.

  * Strictly necessary cookies. These cookies are essential for you to browse our website and use its features. Without these cookies, services like shopping baskets cannot be provided.
  * Performance cookies. These cookies collect information about how you use our websites. This data may be used to help optimise our website and make it easier for you to navigate.
  * Functional cookies. These cookies allow our websites to remember choices you make while browsing and personalise your experience. We may store your geographic location in a cookie for instance, to ensure that we show you the website relevant to your area.
  * Third Party cookies. Third party cookies are those placed by websites and/or parties other than Urban Industries Ltd. These cookies may be used on our website to improve our products or services or to help us provide more relevant advertising. These cookies are subject to the respective privacy policies for these external services, for example, [Facebook Data Use Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).
  * Analytics cookies. We use analytics cookies, like those offered by Google Analytics, to help us understand things like how long a visitor stays on our website, what pages they find most useful, and how they arrived at Urban Industries Ltd.com. To learn more about Google Analytics and your data, visit this [Google webpage](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).

##### **How to control Cookie settings**

Most web browsers allow you to control cookies through their settings preferences. However, if you limit the ability of websites to set cookies, you may impair your overall user experience, as it will no longer be personalised to you. Some browsers offer a “Do Not Track” (“DNT”) signal where you can indicate your preference regarding tracking and cross-site tracking. Although we do not currently employ technology that recognises DNT signals, we will only process your personal data in accordance with this Statement. Below you can learn about how to control cookie settings on popular web browsers:

##### **Pixels**

In addition to cookies, we sometimes use small graphic images known as 'pixels' (also known as web beacons, clear GIFs, or pixel tags). We use pixels in our email communications to you (if you have selected to receive such communications) to help us to understand whether our email communication has been viewed. We also use third party pixels (such as those from Google, Facebook, and other advertising networks) to help us provide advertising that is relevant to your interests.

### **How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions about the use of your personal information, please email privacy@urbanindustry.co.uk.

ICO Data Controller Registration:

Urban Industries Ltd : Registration number:Z1360853

Date registered:13 June 2008 / URBAN INDUSTRIES LTD, 2 PARK VIEW, ALDER CLOSE, EASTBOURNE, BN23 6QE

Unless otherwise stated, Urban Industries Ltd. is a data controller for personal data we collect through the Urban Industries Ltd Products and Services subject to this Privacy Statement. 

Our address is 2 Park View, Alder Close, Eastbourne, East Sussex, BN23 6QE, United Kingdom.

**Privacy Policy Updated: 3rd May 2018**

**Other Points**
